Tomorrow is mystery.
Satan believes he can hit us; he can cause us pain.
That pain will drag us away from Jesus, whereas that pain strengthens our desire the more.
But if you are not a real Christian, pain cannot strengthen your desire.
You can know whether you're a real Christian or just a Christian by mouth.
You see people say, "I'm a Christian". You too are a Christian.
But you are a real Christian by heart.
If you are a real Christian, situations strengthen your desire and determination for God.
This is how we know we are Christians.
Many people keep asking me, "T.B. Joshua, how do we know we are Christians?"
You know you are a Christian when your situation strengthens your desire and determination for God.
Tell your neighbor, "You know you are a Christian
when your situation strengthens your desire and determination for Jesus".
That is when you will say, "Ah, this situation is too much because I'm not a Christian.
Why this failure?"
No, we don't measure our Christian lives by the situations or trials we are going through.
You know you are a Christian when your situations, trials, temptations become the object
of strengthening your desire and determination for God.
"Ah, you are a Christian!"
It becomes an object that strengthens your desire.
Let me give you a good example.
When you are thirsty, there would be a strong urge for water.
Are you with me?
When you are thirsty, there will be what?
A strong urge for what? - For water. You want to drink.
So also, situations cause us urge for who?
For God.
Tell your neighbor, "Situations cause our urge for who?"
[For God.]
Then, you are a Christian.
You pray once in the morning, but because of a situation you have,
you started praying three times.
After a little time, "In Jesus' name" because you believe He is the only who can rescue you.
You have no other way. Situations cannot determine your position before God.
When I say situation, it could be temptation, sickness, hardship, failure.
When you are thirsty now, you cannot sit down.
You will be, "Ah, I need water. I need water". When you now see water, you will be like...
The way you grab it, you want to drink it.
So also, when a situation comes, you run to Jesus!
What is the position of satan now?
He is a foolish man because he is the cause of that situation.
I never knew that the situation is the urge that we have for Jesus.
So when that situation now becomes an object of urge,
the reason why you run to Jesus and satan is the cause of it, he is useless to you.
He has no bearing.
But rather, the opposite is the case today.
When situations come, you begin to lament.
When that one inside you causes you to lament, to cry,
instead of causing you to run to Him and fast more, pray the more,
you now begin to lament, "Why this one?
I go to church always. I don't know why all this. I pray, I fast.
I have not been smoking like before and I have not even been following my friends to party.
I have not been going to nightclubs again.
Why all this?
Even when I was going to nightclubs, I never faced all these crises. Why this crisis?"
You'll know you're not a Christian.
You are just a Christian by mouth.
So I hope you can know whether you are a Christian now.
You can know now.
You know when your situation causes you urge to run to Jesus.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If anyone or anybody is telling you that because you are a Christian,
no situations - ah!
If no situation because you are a Christian, how do you grow in your Christian life?
Ask your neighbor, "How will you grow in your Christian life when there's no situation?"
Ask your neighbor.
[How will you grow in your Christian life when there's no situation?]
Again.
Write it down.
Because those little things, they are things that are disturbing your life.
They are things that disturb your relationship with God.
You are lost already because of situations.
How will you grow in your Christian life when there is no situation?
You cannot grow in your Christian life if only joy, joy, food, food,
progress, progress, breakthrough, breakthrough.
Breakthrough causes us to relax.
When there is breakthrough, that cannot cause you to pray the more.
Rather, you dress well; you have time to comb your hair.
Sitting down, even when you want to come to Jesus. No!
How will you grow in your Christian life when there's no situation?
Like I have said, situations could be barrenness, sickness, poverty, hardship,
setback, temptation of any form.
And these are the things you are now facing.
These are the things that cause you to abandon your post.
Instead of these things to draw you close to God, they are now taking you away from God.
Ok, look at T.B. Joshua today.
You know me. You've read so much about me.
If there is any man of God in the world, because of persecution,
you know more about T.B. Joshua than any other man or God
because you are interested in T.B. Joshua.
Five years ago, they were giving me four years.
"See whether he will spend four years." - You have been monitoring when he will go.
Many of us rebuked, fasted and prayed in the past that this church would collapse - ignorantly.
But you realised that that prayer refused to answer.
You are now showing interest, "I will see".
"Ah, this man! We prayed that he should fall but instead of falling, it´s growing.
What is the cause of all this, my God?"
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So this is why the Bible says that we should not destroy relationships beyond what?
- Beyond repair.
If you have a relationship, relationship is fundamental; it's of God.
When there's trouble, be careful.
Even when you husband and wife want to divorce, that should not end the relationship.
Don't destroy it beyond repair.
If you destroy it beyond repair, the person you are fighting may be a savior tomorrow for you.
How will you meet the person?
MESSAGE TITLE: TOMORROW IS MYSTERY
The person you are fighting, he has done so much against you - so bad.
Whether husband and wife, you want to divorce. Okay.
After the divorce, you continue praying for that man and the man should continue praying for you.
He can give you a call at any time, "Hello. How are you?
I just want to know how you are doing".
Because that relationship has been there.
"Oh, thank you!"
"Happy New Year!" - You may be the first person he will give a call to.
" I just want to greet you."
Let it remain like that because he or she may be your saviour tomorrow.
"No! Over my dead body. We meet in Heaven."
Who told you you will go to Heaven?
Are you with me?
Don't destroy a relationship beyond what?
[Repair.]
No matter what happens.
Tell your neighbor, "Don't destroy a relationship beyond repair".
Yes, satan is our accuser.
And satan is a spirit being.
We are not fighting flesh and blood.
I cannot stand here and begin to abuse the flesh, abuse a person,
abuse the name, call them names, no.
The Bible says we are fighting spirit being, not flesh and blood.
And satan is a type of foolish man that can enter one today,
use the person badly and leave the person.
And the person you see as a satan yesterday becomes a savior tomorrow.
How will you handle the situation if you have destroyed the person?
This is what we are seeing here - deliverance - people that have done a lot being delivered.
Now being delivered, he is becoming a child of God.
If the person had been destroyed,
the opportunity to become a child of God would not be there again.
One thing I know you are lacking is the spirit of forgiveness;
you may have it but not genuinely.
If you have that genuine spirit of forgiveness, you should also forget.
You forgive but you refuse to forget.
The SCOAN Sunday Service.
You do forgive but you fail to forget.
As if what they have done to you, you have not done it to someone in the past.
That´s how you judge yourself.
What they are doing to you, ask yourself,
"Are you saying, you have not done that to someone in the past?"
This is the judgment Jesus gave to this woman
when she was accused and they were about to stone her to death by the law of Moses.
Fortunately, they run to Jesus and asked Him,
"How will you judge this woman?
The law says, anyone who commits adultery should be stoned to death.
Here is the woman now and it is written by our law".
They were looking for something to accuse Jesus Himself, not even the woman alone.
They wanted to bring Jesus into that accusation
so they were looking for something to get Him, as a set-up.
And Jesus said, "Well, it is written in your law
that anyone that committed adultery should be stoned to death".
He now went on his knees and wrote on the ground.
When he wrote on the ground, He looked at it and looked at them,
"Look, what I'm seeing here is,
if anyone of you has never committed what this woman has committed,
such person should stone that woman to death".
They looked at themselves, "It's true. What this woman has committed, I have committed it in the past.
Oh! I've committed it in the past". Immediately they dropped their stones and took to their heels.
And Jesus said, "Where are these people that accused you?"
They could not be found.
And Jesus said, "I have nothing against you. Go and sin no more".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So that is the reason why you have to forgive.
Everything they have accused you of, so bitter.
If you look back, far, you will know that you have also committed it in the past.
Who are you to judge?
Finally, take this word.
When you are at home, sitting down, before you start praying,
there are many things you need to do.
Think about your antecedent, where you are coming from, your past record.
You may not be able to remember when you were little,
but the little you can remember, just bring it to your present.
When you bring all this to your present, you will know that enemies cannot kill you.
It is your fear of enemies that kills you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
They cannot kill you; it's your fear.
When they attack you and fear comes to you, that fear develops hypertension,
heart attack, depression and these things become sickness, leading to death.
Attacks on your business cannot destroy your business.
It is the fear of that attack that destroys your business.
Attacks on your health cannot kill you.
If they give you poison, it cannot kill you but the fear of that.
When you begin to remember people they have given poison to or when you meet your doctor
and the doctor says, "Oh no! Go and write your will", that is fear.
You are dead already.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
There is nothing you have gone through that someone has not gone through in the past.
There is nothing you are facing that someone has not faced in the past
and you know what became of them.
But what is your problem?
Why are you easily forgetting the history?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The Bible is our standard.
Take your Bible and read; you will have your role model.
If you cannot get any role model in this earth,
by the time you read your Bible, you will find your role model in your Bible.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Time is too short.
We have wasted our time on this, our marriage, our education, relationships.
We keep wasting our time, coming back to where we started.
You go this way.
You come back again to where you started.
You go that way.
That is your life. I'm just telling you your life.
"Some day, when I go to America, I will be great after I have spent 20 years there."
After getting to America, after 30 years, you will go back to where you started.
"If I had a billion dollars, I would start a business and become great."
You get the billion dollars and at the end of the day, again back to where you started.
There is nothing you have not tried.
If there is anything you have not tried, it is Jesus!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Tell your neighbor, "If there is anything I have not tried, it is Jesus!"
Because your following Jesus is your own way of following.
You have not followed Jesus genuinely.
You have to say the truth. You have not.
You are hearing from me now that your situation is meant to strengthen your desire, your determination
and this is the first time you are hearing this kind of thing.
And if you have heard it in the past, you have not been putting it into practice.
When trouble comes, you are crying. Is that someone who is following Jesus?
How do we test your faith? You say you are a Christian.
So if you are a Christian now, they should not test your faith?
Anything that is not tested is not genuine.
Tell your neighbor.
[Anything that is not tested is not genuine.]
Because you want to start as fake.
Why are you afraid of tests?
Sickness tests you - you are complaining. How do we know you are genuine?
Failure tests you - you complain. How do we know you are genuine?
Temptation comes - you complain. How do we know you are genuine?
Tribulation comes - you complain. How do we know you are genuine?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Tell your neighbor, "Anything that is not tested is not genuine".
You know the temptation Jesus went through.
A lot of tests.
So when sickness comes, it is a test to know whether you are genuine.
But you keep complaining, "Now I serve Jesus. I know Jesus.
Why is all this happening to me? Why this setback? I don´t know. I'm tired".
Because of that, you don´t pray again.
After a while you continue praying but you have already revoked,
you have complained.
When those things come, it is to remind you, "This is to test my genuineness,
whether I am truly a child of God, for Jesus or fake".
It's a test. Anything that is not tested is not genuine.
Don't cry, murmur, lament when tests come in any form.
You allow tests to separate your marriage.
You allow tests to destroy your business.
You allow tests to destroy your health.
You allow tests to destroy your life.
A lot of marriages today that are supposed to be together -
the troubles that were not supposed to separate them but little trouble - divorce.
Temptation comes - divorce. Sickness comes - divorce.
Hardship comes - divorce.
The same thing, business partner.
A lot of businesses have been scattered because of this temptation.
Church - you stop coming to church because of trouble you are going through.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The area I know all of us have wronged is the way we handle relationships.
Everybody has wronged there.
Everybody is wrong when it comes to that relationship issue
because we have destroyed relationships beyond repair.
No matter what anybody might have done to you, be careful.
Make sure you have not destroyed your relationship with the person
to the extent that in the future, you cannot go to him or her.
Beyond repair is bad.
God always uses people we have fought with, have issue with and see as enemies
to be our savior in the future.
This is what is happening all over the world today.
You just go to many companies. You want business or you need help.
By the time you walk inside the company, you'll find that, "Ha!",
you want to walk back with your back.
"No problem, I will come back."
What happened? Somebody that used to be your driver in the past,
has now become the MD of the big company.
You have done so bad to him.
You now turn back and say, "Ah, I will come back. Oga, I will come back".
You will now begin to ask yourself, "Maybe I have gone to the wrong office".
It was not the wrong office. That was the office you needed to go to.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Tomorrow is mystery.
Thank you. Viewers, thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
TT: Jacqueline Margaret
RV: Mel Flowers 12/08/2018